Hi everyone, I'm Xie Li.
In the Marvelous Designer section,
I will introduce this set of
a bit more like the style of the 20th century,
and how to wear a more casual set of sportswear.
To put it simply,
I will introduce how to use different tools in our software
to create different clothes.
And then I saw on Weibo that
people don't really know how to do this in Marvelous Designer.
Like this,
some of the cladding of the clothes,
and also how to do this kind of folding
of these heavier layers of clothes.
So about these contents of MD,
I'm here to introduce them to you.
So we can prepare
and let's get started.
As for my part,
because I'm using a pre-made video,
so if you are interested in this part,
or if you want to listen to my introduction again,
you can mention it in the comments.
There will be replays.
So let's get started.
There are several ways to make clothes
in Marvelous Designer.
For example,
when we are making a tight type of clothes,
we usually choose to
import a model from Marvelous Designer
and then extract the pattern from the model.
The top of the clothes we just made
is in a tight state.
So it may not be very convenient
if we go directly to the manual drawing of the pattern.
In this case,
I will choose to use
the 3D modeling virtual model tool
to draw some lines on the virtual model.
It may look a bit boring here.
Let's pause for a moment
and play some background music for you.
Wait a moment.
What you see now is
Marvelous Designer 11.
Here are some more repetitive operations.
I choose the area on the virtual model.
Yes.
In fact,
in the previous version of Marvelous Designer,
it can also be drawn on the virtual model.
It's just that some of my friends
don't know that there is such a function
in the 3D modeling tool.
Oh, no.
Then,
after we have finished drawing the selection area,
we can use this extract pattern function
to select these areas
that we have already drawn.
Press the Enter key
and it will automatically extract the pattern.
After extracting,
we will manually
line them up in the 2D window
and place them in the right place.
Because I am a bit of a compulsive person,
I like to place things in a more flat position,
so I will line them up again
in the 2D window.
Then,
we will create the lines between these pincers.
After creating,
we press the Control key
and look at the simulation,
you will see
that this top one
will soon have a line.
After creating a line,
because this is a more compact pattern,
we need to reduce its surface diameter.
Because there is a layer of air
around the virtual model,
this layer of air
is created to prevent
the collision between the pattern
and the virtual model.
Because our virtual model
has a relatively small grid,
and the particle diameter of the pattern
is 20 in the default situation,
this particle diameter is relatively large,
and if the pattern
is too close to the body,
it may be unstable and penetrated.
Therefore,
when each virtual model is inserted,
its default particle diameter
is 20.
In this case,
in order to protect the pattern,
we have a mechanism,
which is the default surface diameter of the virtual model is 3.
So when we make tight clothes here,
we will reduce the surface diameter.
Because later,
we will reduce
the particle diameter of the pattern.
Here,
I will set the particle diameter to 10.
Because we extract the pattern
from the virtual model,
similar to the UV,
to extract it.
So the pattern you extract
cannot be as flat as we manually made.
Of course,
we can also
use some other processing
to turn this pattern
into what you just saw.
Okay,
here,
I just put this,
the physical properties of the pattern,
its fineness,
strength,
and angle of rotation.
You can see here,
I have two angle of rotation.
In the latest version of Marvelous,
Marvelous Designer,
one of the new features is
that the left and right angle of rotation can be changed.
The function of automatic
layout of the pattern
has not yet been manually displayed.
Then,
after we have changed
the fineness, strength,
angle of rotation,
strength,
and angle of rotation,
the advantage of doing this
is that the fabric
will become easy to stretch.
Simply put,
it will not form
that kind of irregular wrinkle.
Because the pattern is too tight,
and the fabric is not easy to stretch,
then the wrinkle will be easy to form.
On the other hand,
when you reduce
these physical properties,
then this dress
becomes flexible.
It is not easy to produce wrinkles.
In addition,
it makes the front of the chest
look very obvious,
and the wrinkles become less obvious.
Then,
let's observe this dress.
After observing this dress,
we will see that
the length of this pattern
is not correct.
First of all,
to make it easier to adjust,
we first delete
the curve points
on these two lines.
Because the curve point
is a point that is
relatively easy to affect
the side line effect.
Some points.
Then we first turn these two lines
into straight lines,
and then let their length
match.
On the side,
you can see that
its wrinkles disappear
and smooth.
Because of the wrinkle,
in many cases,
it is because
the length of the two sides
is different,
wrinkle will occur.
Then,
after we match
the length of the two sides,
its wrinkles will be smooth.
The wrinkles in the side line here.
Ah,
um,
the comment said
the pinch function.
I don't know what you said
about the pinch function.
Is it in the carving?
The pinch function
in the carving
is to
let
the pinch function
in the carving
that we often use
is to make the wrinkles
more
fine.
It is called
the pinch function.
Although I don't know
if you are talking about this.
Okay.
Then,
let's look at
what kind of problem
this dress has.
Here,
it has a very uneven
wrinkle,
right?
In the previous
video,
I actually
introduced
that if you want
to remove
this wrinkle,
first of all,
if you use
the pinch function
here,
which is
the same as
the pinch function
of XiaoYunDouYang,
to press it,
it will shrink,
but the price is
that
because
the pinch function
is
ah,
this is
the flatten function.
It automatically
sets the
wrinkle
between
the lines
as turn.
It is flatten.
Um,
okay.
XiaoMizheng's XiaoMaZhai
is right.
Ah, we are going to add
here.
What is Shen?
Shen is actually
this piece of cloth
to dig out
and only dig
this small triangle
and then sew
the two sides together,
it will become
even.
But adding Shen
is a
little bit
difficult
operation.
So our most difficult
operation is
first of all,
there is a false stitch here,
and then we point
this position
and then point
this position,
these two points
will connect
together.
Ah,
this is why it is called
fake sewing,
that is,
two points
ah,
false sewing
together.
Then when these two points
are sewn together,
we look at
this line carefully,
it is very smooth,
right?
So
we actually
have more
material
between these two points.
Ah,
so we use the
plus point tool
to add a straight point
near the
middle point
of these two points
,
right-click
a triangle
area.
Then after digging
this area,
we can use the
editor
sewing tool to delete
the
false stitch
we used
as a reference
.
After deleting,
you will see that
the curve here
is actually
smoother
than before
.
After adjusting
it like this,
it still
comes out a little more,
so
we
will
enlarge
this gap
a little
.
After reducing it,
let's look at this
clothes.
It is very smooth
on the side here,
there is basically
no
protruding
place
,
so that
our
rope
is already
added.
Okay,
after adding it,
what we are going to deal with next
is these folds
in front of the chest,
because
my last ideal
form is
front of the chest.
What I hope is that
it is not folded,
it is very,
very tight,
but it is very smooth,
and it is very smooth.
In fact,
it is not
too tight
,
but it is very smooth.
In fact,
if you use this tool
before,
I have already explained to you
,
this tool
is
the point
where it
smudges,
it is not
,
uh,
its smudging
is not
directly
flattened,
that is,
the part that is protruding
is flattened,
but this tool
is to reduce the grid,
in fact,
this is what we call
the
tool.
If you
shrink this grid
,
uh,
let me see
my mouse
here,
can you see it?
It will directly
curve
into this
shape,
its curve
will be deformed,
because this grid
is shrunk inwards,
so you can't
use the flattening tool
directly
to smooth
the shen.
Uh,
as for why it can't be used,
you can see
that we used to have a
video about the rabbit girl's
clothes,
I should have
demonstrated it to you,
you can see
that video more
objectively,
why this function
is not used
here.
Okay,
then,
for the front of the chest,
I started to imagine
that we first
sewed a few points
together
with a fake needle
to see
if we
dig
this area
away
,
it may
become flat,
so I
did the same,
take two internal threads,
and then
delete the part
that comes out
in the middle,
then sew up the middle,
after sewing up,
we
delete the
fake needle
at the bottom,
and then
merge these two points,
these two lines,
after merging,
you will see that
the wrinkles
in front of the chest
will become
less,
because all the wrinkles
are like what
Mr. Juefei just said,
most of the wrinkles
are produced,
sometimes
it is
compressive,
but in general,
you have to have
fabric here
for it
to form wrinkles,
so you think
the other way around,
that is,
the fabric here
is very tight,
and it
has no excess
part,
it is generally
not wrinkled,
then
I keep
repeating
these operations
to add a fake needle,
I will find that
there is a
very big wrinkle here,
there is no way
to remove it
because
this model
has a
big chest,
its chest,
this is because
I speed up the video,
so you look
fast,
although I was
also fast,
because the chest
is tight,
the fabric
in the middle
will be more,
and finally
I thought of
a way,
that is,
we can
bend the strength
of the fabric,
when you
bend the strength
to do a
lift,
this fabric
is
not easy
to bend,
so it is
like this
part that is easy
to form a wrinkle,
it will be directly connected
to a curve,
we look at it
here carefully,
when I increase the bending
intensity,
we will simulate
how it will be,
when I
increase the bending
intensity,
because
its bending
intensity
becomes
higher,
it is not easy to bend,
so it can
directly connect
to form a curve,
its wrinkle
will not be
as obvious as
just now,
so when we
adjust it,
we can control
its shape,
after that
I will rotate
to compare
the effect
of the 3D window,
is it
not close to
the effect
I want,
for example,
like this
bottom
here,
it has
some space
I will
put the point
in the bottom
here,
but the upper part
I will not
adjust,
because the upper part
is already
close to the body,
and there is a
gap,
this is why
when I adjust the
wrinkle,
I added a
straight line
on both sides,
because
if a curve
is a continuous curve,
when you
modify it,
without adding
a straight line
as a breakpoint,
it will
affect the
whole curve,
so when we adjust
the curve,
if you
are sure
there is a curve
that you think
is ideal,
then you
add a breakpoint,
break it,
and adjust
the bottom part separately,
or to adjust
the point mainly,
to adjust the line,
in fact,
it is usually used
when the shape is large,
and then
I feel that
this small part
in front of the chest
still has some
protruding parts,
so I will
make the curve
a little bigger,
then you can see
when I make the curve
very high,
almost more than
50-60,
in fact,
this plate
is because
it is very tight now,
that is,
it is now
the overall pressure
is relatively large,
plus,
I have increased
the strength of the toy,
so it basically
has no space
for this cloth
to form a wrinkle,
and then we
put these
other parts
to supplement,
it is also the same
to draw a line
on the body,
after drawing a line,
connect these lines,
and the line
above the rope,
you can't
merge,
but
if you
feel that
this rope
is not easy to draw
this uv
in this position,
you can start from
this point
to the side
to connect a
internal line,
and then
cut it here,
this is an independent
plate,
and then
merge this side
and this side
together,
this is what we
often say
to turn the rope,
you can turn
this rope
from an angle
that comes in
diagonally
to the angle
that comes in
from the side,
of course,
you can see
the previous
video of the suit
and then
remove the sleeve
plate
sleeve plate
because
we just
drew the line
along the
line
of the sleeve
part
to draw
the line
of the
sleeve
part
after drawing
it will automatically
connect with
the plate
just now
this area
is what we
want,
and then
press control
d
to create
a symmetrical
Y-axis
it will automatically
level
the symmetry
no matter
where you put
the 2D window
it is
along the level
along the vertical
direction
to the symmetry
so you can see
although
the two panels
are far away
in the 3D window
it is along
the Y-axis
symmetry
and then
let's take a look
because after
removing the panel
all of our panels
are tight
so when you
start the simulation
there is a certain
gap
and space
so if
we go directly
to the seam
it will have
some
stretching
feeling
there may be
some strange
shapes
so let's
fill in
the extra
part
along the original
line
fill in
the extra
gap
fill it out
and then
include
the Y-axis
here
we also
turn off
the two
vertical points
before using the cut-off point
to delete
of course we cannot
delete it directly
because if we delete it directly
the curve of the curve
will be gone
what we need to do
is to turn the vertical point
into the vertical point
after turning it
this line
the opening
position
is here
right
we need to
connect it
to the sleeve
so we need to
extend
these two points
okay
then look at
the sleeve
on the side
here
because we
used to
extract the panels
directly
it will
go along
the original
UV
so sometimes
there will be
some strange
curve points
of course you can
adjust it
by editing
the panel
or the curve point
tool
or you can
directly right-click
to optimize
the curve point
but I'm lazy
so I will
delete
the curve
of these two lines
and then
now
because there are
no lines
between
the two sides
it will be
very loose
so let's
connect the sleeve
and the clothes
together
this way
we can avoid
it
because the point
of the shoulder
and the stretch
will cause
some strange
curves
no matter
if you are
making tight clothes
or some
loose clothes
you can use
this method
to avoid
creating
the sewing line
between
the two panels
especially
the joint
or the collar
we don't need
to create
the sewing line
which is
very important
so that
they can
match
the natural
shape
here
we pull
the curve
out a little
so that it
matches
the sleeve
section
and then
here
you can see
when I
put the shoulder
and the upper part
of the shoulder
together
is there
a part
that we can't see
it is actually
blocked
so here
we have to
pull it
a little bit
inside
this is the curve
when we change the panel
sometimes
you may feel
a little tired
or
a little bit
tired
this is not
avoidable
you can only
try to understand
little by little
why
there are
more wrinkles
and why
there are
less wrinkles
at the beginning
you may feel
a little bit
tired
or
not
sure
but
after a while
you will
get used to it
well
after we match
it
plus
we set
the physical properties
before
when you sew
it
there is no
wrinkle
and it fits
well
and then
we slightly
modify
its length
so that
the length
of the sleeve
will not
go out
into other 3D software
of course
but if you find it
a bit troublesome
you can
delete it
from this software
and then
because
I had 3D lines
before
the 3d drawing
line
on the virtual model
when it
takes a line
or a version
it does not
apply physical properties
so that
when you apply physical properties
there may be
some placement
deviations
so we can also use these lines
some lines as reference to adjust it. I am here to adjust the position of his shoulders in line with the lines I drew before.
Because I didn't draw the 2D insert, I made the 3D file directly in the 3D window, in the Marvelous Designer.
So I will also think about what kind of clothes I want to make while making the clothes.
So I have a lot of editing process.
Here I applied some negative pressure to him.
Now I want to ask the children, do you know why I choose to use negative pressure here?
I will give you 10 seconds to think about why I used negative pressure on the whole dress.
Do you know what kind of effect I will have if I add negative pressure to him now?
Ok, 10 seconds, time is up.
That's right, I only saw the answers of Hunter9559, Bulei奶茶, and Benny4.
Yes, I also saw Zhang Jinbao.
When I give this board negative pressure, this dress will stick to the body.
When we are making some leather clothes, although in real life, you give this curve intensity,
because the leather fabric, it is very flexible.
It is not very easy to bend.
Everyone should pay attention to whether it is easy to bend or not.
It is not that the fabric you think is very soft, it is easy to bend.
The degree of bending we are talking about is that the overall texture of the clothing is thick.
The leather is usually thicker.
Its pleats are wider and thicker.
In this case, its bending intensity is very high.
It is easy not to stick to the body.
It is also easy not to stick to the body in real life.
So, in real life, we see that this kind of clothes, such as Jiao Yi, its bending intensity is actually relatively low.
We just say that through bending intensity to avoid some wrinkles, it is a little bit similar and a little bit different in real life.
Since I'm going to make a very tight dress here, of course I want it to stick to the body.
So here I gave him a negative pressure to put this board on his body.
Do you understand?
So when we are making this kind of clothes, we want it to be exactly the opposite of making a pillow.
We are giving him a negative pressure to put it on his body.
I want to emphasize this again.
After that, we can finally delete this extra line.
Because now the shape I want is almost the same.
If you double-click on a line, you can select a whole line.
If you double-click on an internal line, you can select a whole internal line.
After that, I'm going to use the distance measurement clothing tool here.
Using the distance measurement clothing tool, you can quickly measure its width on the virtual model.
But here, the way we use this tool is not to measure the entire width, but to make a cut through the editing measurement tool.
Because this board is a very flat board.
Then we created a horizontal measuring board in 3D space.
Ok, after deleting, we copy the whole bottom of the control panel and modify it.
The entire bottom is a flat bottom.
What I'm doing here is to show you that sometimes the board you make or the clothes you make are not flat.
The bottom of the clothes you make is not flat.
Or you want it to be a neat bottom anyway.
Anyway, if you want a neat layout, you can use this 3D clothing measurement tool.
This tool is at the bottom of the measurement tool.
Let me find it for you, it's here.
This tool is for measuring clothes.
After using this tool, you click on it and you can create the clothes measurement.
After creating it, you can move this board.
For example, you want this clothing board to be cut diagonally like this.
Then you use the positioning tool to rotate it diagonally.
After selecting this line, right-click and select cut.
Under the symmetrical menu, these operations are symmetrical.
Because sometimes you put this board, it may be crooked.
After the symmetry is cut, we delete this extra board by clicking delete.
It is a neat bottom board like this.
Do you understand the use of this tool?
Okay, let's talk about it next.
After that, I will replace the bottom board here with a horizontal band.
Because our bottom board, you can see that some children said that the board we made just now was not very neat.
Or his...
Um...
This board doesn't look like the board we imagined.
Then sometimes the overall texture of the board...
Um...
Uh...
The overall texture of the board, we may use the general texture.
But in some horizontal positions, or the position of the edge, we will manually draw some patterns for him.
Then through this method, I will make his bottom board into a relatively horizontal bottom board.
After that, I will replace the original bottom board with a rectangular board.
Then I will cut off some extra parts, and then add a more tight board, and then I will make the bottom board here.
After putting it on, if I want to make some special pattern for the bottom board, I can also make a replacement.
Because the horizontal and vertical board are more convenient to paint.
Um...
Then after that, I found that because the fabric itself is not easy to wrinkle.
But for the sleeve of the model, we still hope...
There are some creases, so I copied a fabric and used this fabric on the sleeve part.
For this part, we will make some adjustments to its bending strength separately.
For example, here I will reduce its bending strength first.
After reducing it, it will be easier to form a thinner and more obvious creasing.
Then I will increase the tension of the gold tail gauze to the foot line a little,
so that it will be easier to form some twisted and not easy to dissipate creases.
Then with the reduction of the particle strength, the creases will become more obvious.
Then we can use some adjustment to the pattern to make some creases in the sleeves.
Although the clothes I made in the sleeves are not visible,
I still want to talk about how to control physical properties here.
Because in fact, when you are using our software,
most of the problems are
...
I don't know how to adjust the physical creases,
so during the entire tutorial,
I will keep reminding you how to adjust the physical properties.
Well, here, I deleted the curve here just now,
because there is no glue on the shoulder here.
Because our version, when we used this leather fabric before,
it was similar to the leather fabric,
its creases are not easy to see.
So, um,
at that time, we would think that the creases are not very obvious.
Now, after the creases are easily created,
it will have some other effects.
For example, here we will see that it has some hollowed out places.
And just now,
the sleeves here, it has some hollowed out places.
Then we need to fix it.
Here, we will see that the protruding position of it is actually the protruding position of the version just now.
Then we will delete this extra part.
Okay.
Then we will just use our hands to tilt this page.
Because the sleeves here...
should be used to close here.
So we will use our hands to tilt this page and then,
our creases will remain the same.
Okay.
After then, we will start making the pants.
Ah, when making the pants here,
it actually Defense Department does not do much more than graduate school students.
Then we will make the clothing,
When drawing 3D lines, you have to pay attention to this kind of place where it is easy to cross some joints, we try to find it in a flat position and draw it.
Then if you draw it directly, it is easy to cross the joint, then you add a few more points, draw a few more points in the middle.
Don't draw this line too long at a time, it's easy to draw too long, because our body is 3D.
It's easy to pick up some weird panels in the middle, so we add a few more points.
Then we select the flat panel as a panel, and then put them together.
The fabric I use is the same fabric as the leather, and then I think it is not obvious.
If you want to make it more obvious, use the fabric we just embroidered.
At this time, because the pants itself is already tight, then we slightly push it a little bit to give it a little strength.
Then we slightly push it a little bit to give it a little strength.
But once you start modeling, this wrinkle will disappear.
Plus, we are still in a state where it is easy to stretch.
So we just copy the fabric in the sleeve and paste it to the pants.
Then we increase its gold-plated sand strength to the foot line tension a little bit.
So that its wrinkle is a little easier to produce.
Then,
we still reduce the particle strength,
so that this wrinkle is a little bit more obvious.
Then I was thinking about what method I could use to make this cat's wrinkle
not become such a flat wrinkle as it is now.
If you use this kind of pattern to make an animation in UV, will it affect it?
In fact, in UV, you can arrange it in Marvelous Designer.
So in fact, if you make an animation, I don't think it will affect it too much.
But this is up to you.
If you have some requirements for this UV, especially the one with thickness,
then you may have to consider it.
Okay, and then the top part, just now,
our top part is actually because it still has some more loose places.
So the wrinkle on the top part will finally come out a little bit more here.
When we pull it to the side, you will see.
Does this place come out a little bit more?
Then what we have to do is that you imagine it.
If you bend it in from this point directly,
then is it that this extra part can be tightened a little bit?
So we also found this curve, pull it a little bit,
let it have more of this dug out part.
After tightening, the wrinkle on the top part will come out all of a sudden.
Then we use the same method as before,
remove the excess part.
Just use that to choose the measurement,
the editing measurement tool to remove the excess part.
Then for the waist,
I made a hole here,
and made it using the inner line directly.
If you want to replace it,
you can do it as well.
Okay, and then the corner here is the same.
I made it using the inner line to cut it a little bit.
Okay, and then sometimes,
I may manually adjust the distribution of the wrinkle.
After adjusting,
I will cool down the pants.
Next, we are going to make the bottom structure of the pants.
This version is Marvelous Designer 11.
Then let's take a look at what I said about the pants part.
It is this part of the structure below.
Because when I started making it,
I didn't think about what style of clothes I was going to make.
So in the end,
I just wanted to make it look like a cartoon style.
So I wanted to make it look like a loose pants.
And then,
I saw that my friend asked me how to make this kind of belt type.
So I made a belt type here.
Then,
I arranged the version first.
After arranging,
I will start sewing.
Because there is no breakpoint here,
there is no reference,
so when I sew,
I usually sew in 3D.
Of course,
this is a demonstration for everyone.
Sewing in 3D.
It's actually the same as sewing in 2D window.
It's just that in 3D window,
when you select the line,
you need to end with double click
to show your line.
The line on one side has been selected.
Then,
here is the end of the double click.
Sew them all.
After sewing,
because if you sew in 2D window,
it will be more troublesome for that point.
So sometimes I sew in 3D window.
Of course,
I am more used to sewing in 2D window.
Because I probably know where it is.
Of course,
it is quite convenient for everyone to use 3D sewing.
Then,
here is the belt part.
Why do I make the belt wider?
Because some of my friends
don't know how to make this type of
sleeves,
or sleeves,
or bandage.
Because you can see that
the bandage I made is wider than the leg.
Because sometimes people will say
that the effect they want to make
is like the one I painted.
That is to say,
it is an independent
and empty state.
It is not like that.
Because if we just simulate
the fabric without making other adjustments,
then the fabric will be down
after you hang it.
But if we
give it a positive pressure here,
because of the pressure,
it will keep blowing up the fabric.
So the fabric will be blown up
as if it is floating in the air.
As if it is floating in the air.
Of course, it is because
it is connected to our sewing line.
It has the effect of the sewing line
with this belt,
so it will not be blown up.
Because it has some gravity.
So if you use MD well,
it has something to do with
learning physics.
The other side is also given.
Sometimes when you make the adjustment points,
the 3D version
will not bend.
It is relatively rare.
Unless you make the adjustment points
with the 3D version,
it will not bend.
Otherwise, it will generally bend.
So we just give it a positive pressure
and hang it up.
After you hang it up,
you will see that this version
is still not in a very level state.
That is because
the position of our sewing line
is the position that we just looked at.
So now we are going to adjust
the position of the sewing line.
Move it a little to the side.
When moving,
you can also refer to
the 3D space.
After we adjust its position,
you can see that
the belt here
is actually
starting to have some
effect of floating.
Then you
put a little more pressure on it,
it will be more level,
more parallel.
Why do we do this effect?
Sometimes some friends
may have to do some special effects.
That is to let this belt
although it has a connection
with other versions,
it is still floating.
For the belt,
it is usually tight.
I have seen some fantasy clothes before,
it will have this kind of
anti-gravity structure.
So it is here to show you
that you can use positive pressure
to do such a floating effect.
Do you understand?
Then we sew the version together.
Okay, sew it together.
After we sew it together,
I will do the crotch part.
In fact, the crotch part is more convenient.
You just draw a few rectangular lines first.
After that,
you will see that
my habit in operation is
to freeze all the unrelated versions.
This can also save some operation time
so that your computer can operate faster.
Okay,
then there are these pants.
For these pants,
I will first
shrink its length.
Why shrink its length?
It is because later,
you can see that the pants I made
have this structure
that will hit the floor.
If you
directly
increase the length
of the belt
and let the belt
drag to the feet,
then you will definitely encounter
a situation where sometimes your belt is too long,
so you can't
pass through the ankle.
Of course, it can also be repaired.
You can pull it out with the
selection grid tool,
but it is a bit troublesome.
So you can use the shrink first.
First,
shrink the pants
in the vertical direction.
Finally,
if we return the shrink to 100,
it will naturally
stretch out while modeling.
So you can see that
the length of the waist
and the overall vertical direction
is 80% of the shrink.
Finally,
I will return the shrink.
Let's make the pants
look like a wide-leg pants.
For the wide-leg pants,
the bottom should be wider
than the waist or knees.
It will be a wide-leg pants.
I didn't think about
what style to make
when I made it.
I think the wide-leg pants
are also good.
Here,
we put the shrink out.
As you can see,
in the moment I changed the shrink,
the length of the pants
is lengthened in the vertical direction.
The length of the pants
is also lengthened
while modeling.
Although it is also instant,
its grid does not
insert the model directly,
but it will
insert the model directly.
Do you understand?
After that,
we change the shrink to 100.
It is now a wide-leg pants.
In this case,
we have given pressure
here,
so even if we untie it now,
it will not be particularly affected.
In this way,
we can do some anti-reverse force effects.
It is still the same.
After that,
I hope that
the overall curve
will be more
close to the human body.
So I choose to add two points
in the middle
and put some inside.
It is not that strange.
It is just that
I want to make
some strange clothes
in my imagination.
They are special clothes.
Mainly because
before I make my own clothes,
I usually do not
make a draft of 2D.
Therefore,
the process I do
seems a little strange.
Only in the end
can I see
what I am doing.